Alexander Miller

alex@thinkmassive.org https://thinkmassive.org https://www.cryptokube.io

SUMMARY

Distributed Systems Engineer with 12 years of experience in startup, enterprise, and SMB environments. Seeking allies on the mission to spread self sovereignty through Free & Open-Source Software and Peer-to-Peer networking. Privacy for individuals, transparency for institutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CryptoKube.io (Denver, CO)

Independent Consultant, Mar 2018 - present

- Architected and built infrastructure for an Ethereum gaming startup (stealth mode)
- ► Released open source Ansible & Terraform code for blockchain infrastructure
- ► Presented Ethereum infrastructure workshop to ~250 attendees at DevCon IV in Prague
- Currently working on Kubernetes configs for Bitcoin, Ethereum, and IPFS

ShapeShift AG (Denver, CO)

DevOps Engineer, Aug 2017 - Apr 2018

- ► Managed cloud infrastructure for a high-security, 24/7 cryptocurrency exchange that processed >\$30MM/day during the peak in Dec 2017
- Operated public frontend+API, internal backend+tooling, >50 blockchain daemons networks/chains
- Built and operated automation tooling for cloud infrastructure, server configuration, and centralized logging, monitoring, alerts, and visualization
- Performed assorted improvements including server hardening, legacy code refactoring, and documenting architectures that evolved organically in a fast-paced startup environment

Endless Computers (San Francisco, CA)

Distributed Systems Architect, Oct 2016 - Aug 2017

- Migrated Endless OS build infrastructure from VMs to AWS using Ansible
- ► Created REST interface for in-house API using Python Flask
- Architected a cloud-based data pipeline for metrics analysis (HDFS, YARN, Hive, Spark, Zeppelin)
- Assisted with analytics queries, data visualization, and generating reports for business stakeholders

Hortonworks, Inc. (Santa Clara, CA & Durham, NC)

Senior Product Specialist - Tools, Jan 2016 - Aug 2016

- ► Led initiatives to centralize tools used by the Support organization
- Automated provisioning of virtual HDP clusters for education and issue reproduction
- ► Conducted weekly analysis of production-down support cases to generate new requirements for SmartSense data collection and rule definitions, assisted w/development
- ► Authored training exercise to certify support engineers on competence of the customer-facing SmartSense tool and use of the backend service (highest participation rate of all exercises)
- Analyzed support case data with a Zeppelin notebook to identify areas of greatest concern

Platform Support Engineer, Sep 2014 - Dec 2015

- ► Supported enterprise customers for diagnosing, reproducing, and fixing advanced components of the Hortonworks Data Platform
- ► Took ownership of problem isolation, resolution, and bug reporting
- Drove internal knowledge management initiatives and assist the frontline support team
- Created Salesforce dashboard, which was opened for use by entire Support organization
- Subject Matter Expert for: AppDev (Storm, Kafka, Pig, Hive), Security (Knox, Ranger, Kerberos, LDAP, SSL), and Hadoop (HDFS, YARN, MapReduce, Zookeeper)

Modea (Blacskburg, VA)

DevOps Engineer, 2013 to 2014

- ► Architected, built, and maintained hybrid cloud infrastructure (AWS + baremetal) for a SaaS platform
- ► Co-developed mobile device virtualization backend
- ► Researched Android platform & internals to optimize device images
- Created diagrams & documentation for both technical reference and marketing purposes
- ► Ansible, Jenkins, Node.js, Mocha, AWS (EC2, S3, CF, ELB, IAM), New Relic, Android SDK, Qemu

Network Operations Manager, 2007 to 2013

- ► Scaled IT operations from 12 inital employees to support >100 employees (vSphere, SAN, Cisco)
- Managed hosting infrastructure at Rackspace for client projects
- ► Maintained annual budget, led disaster recovery initiative as part of business continuity plan
- ► Hired help desk employees, established relationship with MSP to take over expert roles

TacPro Systems LLC (Blacksburg, VA)

Owner, 2013 to 2014

- Performed independent IT services and consulting for small enterprises
- ► Infrastructure improvement plan, P2V server consolidation, backup system repair & upgrades

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Virginia Tech (Blacksburg, VA) *B.S. in Computer Engineering*Certified Bitcoin Professional - Crypto Currency Certification Consortium, 73073f - Mar 2018
Apache Hadoop Administrator 2.x - Hortonworks, license 008-00176 - Feb 2015
Apache Hadoop 2.0 Java Developer - Hortonworks, license 006-00136 - Nov 2014